downloadplex.com 2011-12-06

# Privacy Policy Downloadplex.com

When a visitor requests pages from downloadplex site, our Web servers automatically recognize the browser's domain name, and IP address. Our server do not record e-mail addresses. We collect the domain names and IP addresses in order to aggregate information on the pages users access or visit. This information is collected solely for statistical purposes and is not used to identify individuals. From time to time, we may ask users to provide an e-mail address or mailing address for the purpose of conducting a survey or to provide additional services (for example, subscriptions to e-mail newsletters). Whenever the identity of a visitor is recorded, we will clearly indicate the purpose of the request before the information is requested. 

#### Cookies

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. Some of our partners use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). However, we have no access to or control over these cookies. Please refer to the privacy policies of the network for details. 

[Google Adsense](https://www.google.com/adsense/) uses cookies, including [DoubleClick DART cookie](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/faq.aspx) and/or web beacons to collect information from our visitors while serving ads to our website. This relates to Google AdSense advertisers' use of innovative products and features like Gadget Ads and other offerings in the future. 

  * Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our site and other sites on the Internet. 
  * Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). 
  * Users may update their ads preferences [here](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/). 

We also use other third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. You can see a list of these companies by clicking [here](https://www.google.com/adsense/support/bin/answer.py?answer=94149). You may visit these vendor websites to opt out of cookies (if the vendor offers this capability). 

#### Security

This website takes every precaution to protect our users' information. When users submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and off-line. When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL. While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when you are just 'surfing'. To learn more about SSL, follow this link [http://www.ssl.com](http://www.ssl.com/). 

#### Links

This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we Downloadplex, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site. 

## Downloadplex.com Submission Policy

#### Important Notice

Any persisting efforts to deceive or mislead, including, but not limited to:

  * Fake regular version updates,
  * Multiple sumbissions of the same software product from different sites/URLs or by manipulations in your company name or title (!, $, #, 1, A1 etc.),
  * Submissions of software producing false positive results to encourage or force users to purchase it (e.g. rogue antivirus/antispyware/registry cleaners etc.),
  * Non-software submissions (e.g. online services, guides etc.),
  * Submissions to gain traffic to a non-exclusive software site or URL,
  * Spamming,
  * Affiliate/Reseller submissions,
  * Application HomePage/Download URLs redirects (e.g. tinyurl, other download sites, file sharing services etc.),
  * Efforts to get higher visibility for your listing by providing invalid affiliate data, using any leakage technique for prevention of affiliate tracking etc.,
  * Efforts to expedite your submission by providing back link URL from other's site or from an orphan (not linked from anywhere) page on your site,

will cause ALL YOUR LISTINGS to be removed from our database and your IP/URL to be banned for all further submissions!

#### Submission Terms

  1. You must be the software author or the person who has been given the right to submit it.
  2. The software must NOT infringe on any copyrights or international treaties.
  3. We do not accept software bundled with third party advertising (Adware) or tracking components (Spyware).
  4. The software must be virus-free.
  5. In most cases we only accept submissions for stable versions. If you send us a submission for beta or other unstable product release, we will more than likely decline your submission.
  6. The software interface and all its documentation must be IN ENGLISH.
  7. The download URL should take to a program file and NOT to a web page.
  8. Both PAD file and program file must be ALWAYS accessible from your server.
  9. The software must NOT request your email address or other personal information before you can download and/or use it.
  10. The software must provide users with a clear and simple method for its removal.
  11. We reserve the right to remove any software listing from our database for reasons at our own discretion.

#### Software types we do NOT accept

  1. Online Casino & Gambling,
  2. Anything of an "Adult" nature,
  3. eBooks of any kind,
  4. Browser Search Toolbars,
  5. Warez, cracks, or any other application type that breaks copy-protection,
  6. Applications designed to spam the USENET,

## About PAD

#### What is PAD?

PAD is the **Portable Application Description** , that helps the software authors provide product descriptions and specifications to online sources in a standard way, using a standard data format that will allow webmasters and program librarians to automate program listings. PAD saves time for both authors and webmasters. More information can be found [here](http://www.asp-shareware.org/pad/).

In order to use the advantages of PAD, you should produce a PAD file in XML format for each software. Please refer to the latest version of [PAD specification](http://www.padspec.org/spec.php) and pay your attention on strings format and strings length to create PAD files that are compatible with PAD enabled web sites.

To produce your PAD files in a simple way, you may use free [PADGen](http://www.padgen.org/) tool. Then, you can submit your software only by entering the PAD file URL to the most of software download sites - the list of PAD enabled sites is available here: <http://www.asp-shareware.org/pad/padsites.asp>.

#### Accepted PAD Files

Your PAD files should be compatible with [PAD specification](http://www.padspec.org/spec.php) version 2.0 or higher having included the **< Program_Category_Class>** field (older versions did not specify the category listing within PAD files). For creation of valid PAD files please use the freeware [PADGen](http://www.asp-shareware.org/pad/padgen.asp) with version number 2.0 or higher (the current version is 3.x) that fully supports this format.

The following fields in PAD file are **required** :

     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Company_Info><Company_Name>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Company_Info><Company_Website_URL>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Company_Info><Contact_Info><Contact_First_Name>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Company_Info><Contact_Info><Contact_Last_Name>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Company_Info><Contact_Info><Contact_Email>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Program_Info><Program_Name>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Program_Info><Program_Version>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Program_Info><Program_Release_Month>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Program_Info><Program_Release_Day>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Program_Info><Program_Release_Year>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Program_Info><Program_Type>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Program_Info><Program_Install_Support>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Program_Info><Program_OS_Support>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Program_Info><Program_Category_Class>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Program_Info><File_Info><File_Size_K>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Program_Descriptions><English><Char_Desc_80>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Program_Descriptions><English><Char_Desc_2000>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Program_Descriptions><English><Keywords>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Web_Info><Application_URLS><Application_Info_URL>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Web_Info><Application_URLS><Application_XML_File_URL>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Web_Info><Download_URLS><Primary_Download_URL>

The following fields in PAD file are optional:

     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Company_Info><Country>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Program_Info><Program_Cost_Dollars>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Program_Info><Program_Change_Info>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Program_Info><Program_System_Requirements>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Program_Info><Program_Language>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Web_Info><Application_URLS><Application_Screenshot_URL>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Web_Info><Application_URLS><Application_Icon_URL>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Web_Info><Download_URLS><Secondary_Download_URL>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Affiliates><Affiliates_eSellerate_Product_ID>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Affiliates><Affiliates_Plimus_Product_ID>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Affiliates><Affiliates_Regnow_Product_ID>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><Affiliates><Affiliates_ShareIt_Product_ID>
     <XML_DIZ_INFO><ASP><ASP_Member_Number>

#### PAD Creation Tips

  * Do NOT specify the software version in PAD file name! When updating your software product on the web you will have to **update the existing PAD file** and NOT to create a new one!
  * Provide your **valid email address** in **Contact Email Address** field to be able to receive PAD polling error reports, update and review notices etc.
  * Do NOT specify the software version in **Title** field (e.g. "your-software-name v.2.01", "your-software-name 2.01", etc.) but ONLY in **Version** field of your PAD!
  * Do NOT include the license information in your software name (e.g. "your-software-name single user license", "your-software-name 25 users license", etc.)!
  * Specify the same software name in PAD file as provided on your web site! Do NOT add any descriptions and/or any other unwanted information in **Title** field!
  * Do NOT include the software name and/or any other unwanted information in **Company** field - this will only prevent to search the software by company name!
  * The **Screenshot URL** must take DIRECTLY to an **image file** and NOT to screenshots page on your web site!
  * The **Icon URL** must take to an image in a web-supported format (GIF, JPG or PNG, **NOT in ICO format!** ) having size 32x32 pixels!
  * The **Download URL** must take DIRECTLY to the program file and NOT to download page on your web site!
  * **Affiliates** PAD extension is intended ONLY for establishing the affiliate partnerships between you and the download sites, so if you do NOT support affiliate partnerships via current payments service, do NOT fill the appropriate field but leave it empty!
  * To **change the PAD file URL** just set the PAD XML File field of the **old** PAD file taking to the **new** PAD file location so that on the next polling round our script could pick it up automatically.
